All
right, my friends. Welcome to the
complete set review for Reality Fracture
Multicolor time. We do white, blue,
black, red, and green. you miss those,
go watch them on YouTube. Like the
comment, like, comment, subscribe,
support the content, throw a hype in
there. A lot of work goes into a set
review, of course, and I couldn't do it
without your support. So, please support
me. I'm begging you. All right, come on.
>> You had one job.
>> One job. Hit the button, the like
button, support the content. All right,
so we're getting into multi killer now,
which is a very big, very important
section. Uh, all of all the cards
constructed and limited. Uh, as always,
here at the awards, you know, and love
building up to 10 new brews happening on
Wednesday while I'll be playing a bunch
of these new cards. I am stoked to build
uh these 10 new decks. This set looks
like so much fun. I'm amped for it,
which is great. And uh don't forget also
that we are brought to you by Anthos,
folks. Take care of yourselves. All
right, invest in your body. The Anthro
chairs are not cheap, but they are worth
every single penny. Uh because your
body's worth it. You spend a third of
your life sitting, whether you're
working, gaming, whatever else it might
be. And you deserve to have a chair that
will support your body properly and not
wreck your back. All right? We're
getting older and you're going to want
to take care of yourself. Don't want to
be 45 and be like, "Oh, I'm an idiot.
What was I doing?"
So, check out Anthos. Link in
description. Promo code Jim DG for $20
off your order. Anthos fix your sit.
Let's get right in. Fate Hold
Chronologist. I I use that for her
Miller. Anthos is better. Love it.
Fateold Chronologist is a two mana one
two flyer. It is a hybrid card. There's
one of each uh there's one hybrid card
for each color pair in the set. So some
decent multiolor things happening here.
And two mana for one two flyer which is
not very good. It has the peer review
prepared spell which is a sorcerer for
three mana mega two two and surveil one.
Again I actually like this a lot. Uh,
this peerreview spell is on multiple
cards in the set. I think it's on one
white card, one blue card, and now on
this card. And that's sweet. Honestly, I
like the the uh kind of toning down the
complexity a little bit by having the
same spell multiple times. This card's
fine. It's like a curve in and of
itself, but not a very good curve. You
know, a one two fly over two is pretty
bad these days, and then a two two for
three is also pretty bad these days. So,
I think this guard is pretty filler
level. Uh, it does allow you to surveil
off peer review and the blue mechanic
theme is, you know, payoffs for
surveillance scry, but I think this
card's kind of kind of kind of fillery.
So, not a big fan of the chronologist,
but it's just okay.
Signpost uncommon for uh for fateold. Of
course, these are the there are the five
hex haven schools for your allied colors
and then the enemy colors have their own
themes. Is a four mana 3 four flyer,
which is obviously very good. Be in
combat in your turn. Another creature
you control gets plus one end on a turn.
And if you scride or surveil this turn,
put a counter on it instead. That's a
big deal. Uh, all right. So, scry, go to
combat, add a counter. Scry, go to
combat, add a counter. That's a good
place to be and a good payoff. Um,
there's some A plus B happening here.
You need to have things that scry and
surveil and then things that pay you off
for it. This is a good payoff though at
a pretty good rate. Uh, so, you know, I
think we're fly over for four with some
big upside. Uh, it's great stuff.
Constructed unplayable obviously. Then
we get a fate hold charm. And the charms
in a set are pretty good. There's only
only charms of the allied colors of
course for the hex haven schools. And
fade old charm is two mana for an
instant as they all are. Choose one of
three. Draw a card. Empower Jace 2. More
on that in a second. Return a target
spell or creature to its owner's hand or
give your team plus one plus two. So
what does empower Jace 2 mean? Empower
Jace is effectively just like a mass uh
where if you don't already have a Jace
Plains Walker token, you make one and
then you add that many loyalty counters.
If you already have one, just add the
counters to it. And Jay is very simple.
Uh minus one surveill one minus three
draw a card. So uh in the case of the
charm here, empower Jace 2 effectively,
it's either scry twice or build up into
a draw. Uh which is pretty good, you
know. So draw a card and surveil twice
or draw a card and then draw two/3 of
another card is pretty good for two
mana. Not amazing uh but pretty good.
Two mana unsummon or two mana for uh
unsubstantiate is fine and then pump a
team is also fine. One of the key
factors to evaluating a charm is that
one of the modes is a lot better than
the others as kind of your default mode.
So boros charm deal four to your
opponent. It has other modes. That's the
primary mode. This card doesn't really
have a good primary mode. I think all
three modes are fine. Uh not fantastic.
And that makes me a little uh not
thrilled about the uh the fateold draw.
I think it's only okay. It's fantastic
and limited. But as far as constructive
goes, I think there's too much
competition for this. I think this could
be like a one of maybe or like you know
a flex card kind of thing. Uh I don't
think draw card slow surveil is really
worth it. you know, uh, the Prismari
charm, for example, is, you know, draw a
card, surveil to immediately with no
with no thing, and that's still only
just fine. Um, unsubstantiates also not
a good card by itself. It's no remand.
It's okay. It's fringe. So, I think this
card is very, very fringe. It's a play
worse than it looks. Still great and
limited. Um, but yeah, Fatal Charm. And
again, there's your J token. Uh, put it
in your head. We're not going to see it
again. Prudent Fate sealer is your
hybrid signpost. the metaphor a 14 and
it's prepared review scrier surveil pump
the team plus O but only one's turn and
also has again has pure review and again
I love this I really love this design
choice to put the same prepared spell
multiple cards again great complexity uh
down tuner or whatever
get the idea uh but yeah this car is
pretty good one four and a two two for
three and three is fine a little bit of
a pump plus is pretty cool too so yeah
it's fine It's an okay limited card.
Nothing too crazy. Then we have Proctor
of Potential for a 3-1 whenever it
enters another creature you control
enters surveil one and you can spend two
mana to return to the graveyard with a
finality counter on it, but only if you
scride or surveiled this turn. Kind of a
weird blue white card. I guess it like
kind of makes sense cuz white ranates
two, but this card's kind of great. I
mean 3-1 and then constant surveilling
over and over again. This is your
classic payoff and enabler uh where you
are playing this, you're getting your
surveills and it also pays you off for
surveilling too. Bringing it back,
having two three ones for two mana each
time is great. I don't think the
surveile archetype will really make it
in constructed. Uh this is a windmill
slam and limited. Uh insanely good.
Constructed maybe, probably not, but
this card is pretty awesome. Uh
unbounded surveillance is great, too.
Card's good. Good rare, great limited
card. Fringe constructor card.
Denzel Fateold. This is the the school
leader for Hexhold Hex Hex Haven. Uh
instead of dragons, there's sphinxes
here in the alternate reality. For air
34 flying flash. Pretty good stat line.
If you scrier surveil, put a counter on
each creature you control.
It's pretty good. Uh ridiculous
ridiculous limited bomb. like windmill
slam, do a backflip card's insane.
Three, four, flying flash for four is
already good enough in limited, but
pumping your team over and over and over
again is ridiculous. Constructed again,
I don't really think this uh scry
surveile theme has a lot of uh of legs
in constructed, maybe it does. You know,
it's kind of cute with the uh the one
mana plan, white plan where creature
EDBs, scry, and then puppet team. You
have four of them. It's kind of cute,
but uh yeah, but limited bomb. Probably
not the constructed, but really bombers
unlimited. When we got to Boros, we see
Charge the Sanctum as the hybrid card
through metaphor, a instant uh plus two
plus for the team or give a single
creature plus two plus and a counter. I
mean, this card isn't that much
different than all the cards like this
in limited. If you're going wide, it's
fine. Has a bit of a buyout if you
aren't going wide. Fringe limited card,
nothing more.
Mabel a valley hero one of the signpost
uncommons they met up for a one two
whenever it or another creature enters
put a counter on a creature you control
enter this turn so by itself you can
it's a two three and then every other
creature you play uh can have a counter
on it or put a counter somewhere else
that's pretty cool uh the red white
theme is kind of like plus a counter
aggro uh which is cool this is a fine
little card I think this is it looks
kind of small but play better than it
looks um you know having a counter for
every creature you play is really really
nice. So thinkable is very good. Good
limited card.
Warriors Blade is the other uh signpost
uncommon for red white four mana four
and equipment when it enters you.
>> Oh, IT'S LIGHTNING HELIX. OH MY GOD.
>> Lightning helix something and it gives a
creature plus two plus one equip for
three but one less for each counter on
the creature it targets. So pretty good.
Four mana for a helix is fine but not
great. Uh and then of course equip will
be maybe two most of the time which is
also fine. Pretty good card you know.
Kurd bent blade adjacent. Uh again very
nice art not playable instructed but
cool limited card. Solitary cell is our
boros rare to infer an artifact when it
enters. Exile target non-land permanent
an opponent controls man three or less
until it leaves the battlefield and then
one tap discard a legendary card and
draw a card. So kind of like a super
glass casket. Uh whereas Glass Casket
with only creatures, this is any
non-land permanent. Pretty big upside.
Uh Glass Casket is a playable card. It's
obviously much harder to cast. Uh but
being an artifact is pretty cool, too.
Some synergy there. And then legend
legendary uh you know, kind of fail safe
is kind of cool. Not that important, I
don't think, but you know, not the worst
card's fine. Feels more like an uncommon
than a rare to me, but it's a solid
card.
Moving on to uh so no mythic for Boros.
Again, Boros is not one of the schools.
The allied color schools have the
mythics. So, then we have Theix Metam
Mage. This is the common uh Theix
Theorix, sorry. Theorix card. The
metaphor a 23 and prepared has threshold
plus flying and has the omit variables
prepared spell one mana mill three. Blue
black's all about milling getting
threshold. This is not a bad way to do
that, you know. Uh 33 fly over three is
pretty good. Little extra mill. a little
underpowered but that's fine overall.
Okay, limited card. Paradox Shaper is
the hybrid Demir card. So for a one
three and if you're upkeep if it's not
prepared prepare it again two mana up a
card in the bottom and then you can cast
the variables every turn. Pretty good
enabler. Uh this can be you know one
mana mil three every turn. Also prowess
is in blue red. This is a spell you can
cast every turn for prowess. It's pretty
good too. There's definitely a lot of
really nice cross uh archetype synergy
in the set where the cards the colors
that are adjacent really have some cool
cards that seem to go into both
archetypes which is very very nice. Uh
and again we see omit variables again
the same the same prepared spell. Love
this. Very clever.
Uncommon
signpost for blue black is formula
recursive recruitment sorcery make two
cadetses and then it was cast in the
graveyard. put a counter on each of them
for every three cards in your graveyard
and then flashes back for eight. So big
time late game card. Totally fine to
play on turn four. 22s for two is
reasonable enough. Uh but when you flash
it back, you're making some pretty big
chunkers. You know, maybe two fives, two
sixes on a card that's already good in
the front side, a card that's good to
mill. This card's nice. Speaks to a
wanting to play a longer game. the kind
of card where if the format goes long in
limited, this would be a unbelievably
good card. And then a constructivist
card is not playable, but it's still a
pretty sweet one. And then we come to
the Theix Charm two for instant choose
one. Uh spell pierce disfigure or mill
three and draw a card. Again, a spot
where none of these effects are really
worth two mana. I mean, spell pierce
costs one, disfigure costs one, mil
three draw card costs one. So I don't
think you're getting a great deal here
and I don't think that any of these
cards is powerful enough to really
warrant what you're trying to do. Two
manifest is tough. Mil three draw a card
not quite good enough. Another charm
that will play well unlimited but I just
don't think really gets there and
constructed. It's close but I don't
really think so.
Null summoner is the rare form for a 42.
When it enters, if you cast it, target
reveals their hand, hits an online land
cover from it and exile it. And then at
threshold, you may uh cast the exiled
spell, which is cool. So 42 thoughts
with some upside. Uh pretty fragile
body, but kind of a powerful effect.
Great and limited constructed. I don't
think it's right there.
The mythic for uh Therax is Ulderos
Therax. This is the Demir Elder Sphinx.
Six mana for a five flyer. Very powerful
effect. When it enters, if you cast it,
exile up to one target non-land card of
each type from your graveyard. Copy them
and you may cast any number of them.
Total mana value six or less among all
the cards you choose. Um that's pretty
powerful. You know, you can cast a a
creature and a removal spell and a card
draw. Let's say you cast opt doom blade
on a three drop or whatever. That's
pretty powerful, but it once you have a
full graveyard, you got to actually cast
it. It cost six mana. It's a five5. It's
pretty cute with superior Spider-Man as
you are actually casting it. The whole
cast trigger thing, which is nice. I
card is really powerful. It's a a
bonkers limited card
constructed. I just don't think this
card is necessarily uh better than
Deceit at the same cost. Also the same
synergy as Superior Spider-Man. It could
be like a one or two of in the Superior
Spider-Man deck for sure. It's
definitely reasonably powerful, but adds
a bit of you and might just not do the
thing you want it to do, but it's cool.
Really fun card. Great bomb unlimited.
On to Golvari, which again has no
school. Witherloom is not in the set.
Barosity of the Hunt for an enchantment
flash enchant creature plus mo and death
touch and then when it dies bring it
back tapped pretty good card you know
like uh pluso and death touch and then
return it when it dies is serviceable a
little risky if they like were to kill
it in response you get blown out but a
fine little trick uh it is of course a
black or green card so you can play it
in your black red deck you play it in
your blue green deck whatever else it
might be uh more cool art which is very
very nice. Uh but yeah, this card is
pretty good. Pretty solid. Pretty solid
draft cards. Be careful they don't get
blown out. Uh if you can avoid it.
Hatra, the desert fang. Five mana for a
three- three. When it enters for each
opponent, uh put X minus one as counters
on one creature uh that player controls.
Rex raise mana value on cards in your
graveyard. There are land cyclingers,
but I think just playing this card
normally is totally fine. just like play
magic cards go to the bin on turn five
you play so it'll kill something and
that's awesome so great limited card
unplayable constructed
primal witchalker is the metaphor a 2-1
menace EDB mill 4 and when you do return
target land card your graveyard to the
battlefield tapped so a two-1 that gets
a land play is pretty cool it can get
dual lands surveil lands get any land
notch basics which is kind of nice and
uh again this sort of cross archetype
synergy here which card plays well with
all of your deir theix cards which is
kind of cool. So that's the mark of a
good limited set. Uh there was very
little of that in the Hobbit which is
why um
>> you know it's wasn't that good of a set.
Uh but in this set there's a ton of it
which which is usually like the you know
the hallmark of a great limited set. So
I'm very stoked for the set for limited.
Uh yeah card's pretty good. It's decent
value. Not very big but it's a fine
card. Construct I don't think so. But
Verasa the cutting glare.
This card is kind of nice. Black green
for a 44 death touch for three.
That's chunky. And then it says ver when
Verasa enters you control six or more
lands. Destroy target permanent and
opponent controls and they make a
treasure token.
That's pretty good. Uh fine on turn
three, phenomenal on turn six. If you
are ramping in any which way which way
blands of course uh
card's pretty sweet this is clearly a
you know ridiculous bomb unlimited. Uh
also looks like Carrian for all you
Stark fans out there more overlords
>> but constructed. I think this card is
pretty cool. I mean I don't know want
what deck wants this card exactly but I
think this card is not that far out
there. Uh destroyer permanent on a 44 is
pretty uh is pretty sweet. And even
though you need to have six lands, it's
still cheap. It's only a three drop, so
you can play this and something else.
Um, you know, Golgvari mid-range, one of
those decks that's been on, you know,
tier three for like five years. Uh,
maybe could be a revitalizer here. But I
think this card is pretty sweet as your
sleeper card. Uh, Verasa cutting glare
ridiculous bomb in uh, in limited.
Next up, we have our red green cards.
Constari
Constari improviser mana for two two
anders prepared has soul tether a spell
that's uh three mana and make a
heartwood token which is a mana rock
catast for red or green this card's nice
you know barrett some upside it ramps
red green is all about ramping uh making
his heartwood tokens some artifact
synergy too and that's sweet uh plays
well in you know green and blue ramp
plays well plays fine in you know red
white or whatever uh it's good good
solid common not amazing Not insane,
just good good solid card.
On the opposite side of the ball,
>> good lord
>> is uh
>> the craft work crusher. Seven mana for a
75 trample. When it enters, choose two
four-door creature to plan walker. Make
a 22 or draw a card. Any one of those
deals is fantastic. Uh you know, 75,
kill a thing, draw a card, awesome. 75,
kill a thing, 22, awesome. 75 22 draw a
card. Awesome. Uh, bonkers limited card.
Record is all about ramping and this
card does that very, very well. So, uh,
even without the ramp stuff, it's still
really good. With the ramp stuff, it's
even better. Uh, bonkers limited card.
Ridiculous. Really, really good.
Canari charm is red green for the charm.
Choose one six damage to a flyer. Put
two plus counters on a creature and
against trample or add three colorless.
What are we going to do with that? Uh
I mean this is the most bizarre of the
charms. Uh it can ramp you sort of which
is weird. Uh
plummet is very fringe. The best mode
here is plus two trample uh two counters
and trample which is weird because like
that plays more into Boros than into
into Grul as far as the uh the draft
archetypes go. It does make the card
pretty solid and limited where I think
like two mana, two counters and tramples
is kind of excellent. Um,
that being said, I think it's pretty
weak overall. It's a fine limited card,
but don't think I want to play this
card. So, moving on.
Next up, we have woodwork prodigy. This
is the uh uncommon hybrid for a 33. Then
if you're upkeep, if not prepared, it
becomes prepared and it also has soul
tether. It has the three mana, make a
heartwood. That's pretty sick. Uh you
just keep making heartwood every single
turn uh for your ramp payoffs. Get more
artifacts in play. Good base level uh
value, too. This card's nice. Not
incredible, but good solid body, good
ability. Uh and then again, don't forget
this is also a mono red card, so you
could play this potentially in your blue
red prowess deck and just cast a spell
every turn. Um,
yeah, this card's nice. I'll keep
prepared. Cast it. I'll keep prepared.
Cast it. Really good stuff. So, cool
card. Not a not a, you know, a
ridiculous card, but very, very nice.
Then we have Tenurard Tether Mage. This
card's awesome. To for a 1-1. When it
enters may sacrifice a land, and if you
do, uh, make two tapped Heartwood tokens
and you can tap two untap artifacts you
control and put two plus encounters on
this creature. So, usually Heart would
come in untapped. uh and they can they
can bump this thing up. The ones it make
come in tapped so you can it'll get your
mana back. But this card is great,
right? It's uh it ramps you makes two
artifacts can get pumped up or whatever.
Really cool card. Great in limited in
constructed it's probably not there. It
does make two artifacts out of one card.
So like if you're playing the sacrifice
deck maybe more things sacrifice and so
on. Uh but for limited cards great uh
really really cool card. And then the
sphinx for uh for Constari is Ariad
Constari. Formula 4 a 54 flyer when it
enters or dies make a heartwood token
and then six mana make a heartwood token
and gets plus x plus o to end of turn x
number of artifacts you control. So a
five fly over four EDBs to make a uh
heartwood and dies to make a heartwood's
pretty good. Uh ridiculous rare
unlimited where like you play it you
ramp it's huge. They got to kill it you
get more ramping and then more mana.
Awesome stuff. Uh, constructed probably
not good enough, but honestly not that
far off. I mean, 54 flyer for four with,
you know, ramping upides. Pretty sweet.
So, pretty cool card. Don't know what I
would want this card, I guess, but uh,
yeah, Heartwood was left and right.
Really cool. Then we come to is it uh,
Twin Vision is the hybrid common for an
instant draw card and if it wasn't cast
from your hand, draw two cards instead.
So, cool prowess card. just play it for
prowess triggers flashback three mana
discard a card and draw two which is
pretty good honestly. Um this can be
used for your blue black threshold deck
uh put in the graveyard and whatever. Uh
this is also a sweet card for your prow
deck more spells. Uh this card's cool
you know and then obviously if you're
just flooding a little bit in the mid
game unlimited just a land draw two
cards.
Um
yeah, cool. You know, it's uh think
twice Jason for sure. Card sweet. It's
also a monor red card which is nice too.
Oh yeah, good card. Good draft card.
Very good off tablet. That is true. So
if uh if this card were to see play
constructed, it would be off the tablet.
I mean most things are good off tablet.
Clash of Elements. One of the uncommons
for a instant uh two online permanent.
Its owner may put it on top or bottom of
their library. sorry, put it on top of
their library. And if they do, they take
two, and if they don't, put it on the
bottom. So, this is a a pseudo vindicate
uh in blue red where they can keep it if
they want, but they got to take two,
which is pretty cool. Uh so, this can
hit artifacts, enchantments, planes
walkers, a lot of things that Blue Red
usually can't hit, as well as large
creatures. So, it's cool. It's fine
card, not amazing, but a solid uh
removal spell.
Sahili, Jewel of Avishar, pump up for a
two4. Thus, have haste. Play an creature
spell, make a thopter, and then no cap
on uh how many you can make. Card's
awesome, phenomenal limited card. Uh in
your prowess deck, you just play some
cantrips, go token, token, token, they
all attack immediately. Fantastic. Great
limited card. Not good enough for
constructed, uh but fantastic limited
card.
Pretty
cool card. Frostbite pyromental
uh joining the ball lightning cycle uh
with uh lightning skelemental blue sorry
red blue for a 44 trample haste and
shows combat damage to a player. You
draw two and an endstep sacrifice it. So
the most aggressive divination of all
time.
>> Very agree. pretty cool card. You know,
imagine playing like a blue red burn
deck and just popping this bad boy in
there. I mean, dealing four and drawing
to is kind of insane. Uh
yeah, this card's cool. I don't know
what deck wants this card, but it's the
kind of card that could spawn a new
archetype, I think. And then if you have
somebody give a double strike and draw
four or bring it back for the, you know,
whatever kind of effect. Um really cool
stuff. Yeah, I mean this card's dope. Uh
really, really cool. Don't know if it'll
actually find a home in constructed.
This is the kind of card that like I
could maybe span back to Pioneer.
Probably not modern, but um yeah, card
sweet. Really, really cool card. Really
fun and limited, too. Just a solid, you
know, just deal four, draw two is kind
of nice. So, big fan. Frostbite
Pyromental.
Moving on to Oroz. Blessed Ghoul. One
mana for a one lifelink hybrid. They
might return back to your hand. I mean,
this kind of card is often playable and
limited. Having the flexibility of being
white or black is pretty cool and
lifelink's not bad as far as just like
you know chunk block gain a life. Chunk
block gain a life is pretty cool. Also
important to note that uh you know black
has all these self-mill effects. So you
can mill it and then white has the life
gain effects from uh from bigger bloom.
So there's a lot more going on here than
just you know kind of random you know
whatever card like there's a lot of
synergy happening too. And um yeah I
mean pretty cool little common. Not a
card you want a lot of. Kind of a late
pick, but kind of a cool fun utility
card.
Edgar, ancient bloodlord
for a two three. Never another creature
plan walking control dies. You gain one
life and then two mana sacrifice another
creature. Plains walker put a counter on
this and he gains menace. Cool little
sacrifice payoff. There's really like a
major sacrifice theme uh in black and
white. Like kind of a little bit but not
really. Uh doesn't drain either. You
only gain again some cross synergy with
the uh vigor bloom life gain stuff. It's
a fine limited card. It's not good
enough for constructed but it's a fine
limited card. Casted fates five mana
destroy nine permanence and put a
counter each creature target player
controls. I mean this is your bread and
butter awesome limited card. Like
>> yes that's awesome.
>> Five mana kill a thing get maybe four or
five you know power on top of worth of
value. Awesome. Great limited card.
Unplayable, constructed. It's classic.
Vindictive Triumph. This is uh some
story beat, right? Liliana
looking to be kind of necromancing her
mono white doppelganger to do some
rainbows. Rainbows are cool, right? Um
Black one instant exile creature planes
walker. If it mana value is three or
less, return to the battlefield tapped
under your under your control and then
exile at the beginning of next endst
step uh similar to there's a mono black
card like this. It's a sorcery that I
really liked that come back wrong maybe
but wasn't really good enough. Um making
an instant hitting planaines walkers
pretty cool. Bringing it back tap means
you you need ETB effect or a loyalty
ability to kind of really use it. Um but
it's pretty cool and again it can kill
anything. So, this is Hero's Downfall
with a ton of upside and exiling is a
big deal, too. If Black is a deck in any
capacity, this card's super playable.
Not a four of, but definitely a uh a
really good one or two of kind of like
in that flex spot. Uh,
and you can kill it on the endstep and
then untap with it. True. So, you get
one attack with it. That's great. So,
uh, yeah, cool card. Super sweet.
Whiplash Wordsmith as we're on to
Stinger Quill here for a 33 and is
prepared as long as an opponent was
dealt non-combat damage this turn.
Flying in haste. Pretty big deal. And
then Vicious Verse one mana ping your
opponent for one again. Uh Singer Cole
was all about uh non-combat damage
triggering stuff like this card. Fine.
Uh not amazing but fine, you know,
serviceable card. Not particularly
great.
Grim Repriser. It's metaphor for a two2
prowess.
Red black to return this guard and your
graveyard to the battlefield with a
finality counter on it, but only if
opponent took non-combat damage. Pretty
good two prowess for two is like pretty
solid card. And then the uh you know
come back at some later points. Great.
Uh just you know any vicious verse which
is on like four different cards will
trigger this and get it back which is
sweet which is nice. Good solid two drop
for your black red aggro deck.
Stinger quil charm.
Now you might say, Jim, you've poo pooed
the charms a lot.
Why best to show distinker vulgar?
This one's nice. All right, this one is
two cards that are a shade below
playable on their own. Lightning strike
and two two haste for for two.
It puts those two things together and it
gives you a third mode which is
definitely much more fringe but kind of
what a deck like this wants where what's
the fear when you're playing a low to
the ground ratos aggro deck they play
some big huge blocker and you can't get
through it right this allows you to
attack into it first strike and death
touch effectively a doom blade they
could block but um and it allows
everything to attack which is cool too
the problem with this card is of
Will there be a Ratosse deck that can
take advantage of it because you could
only play it in a low to the ground
really aggressive Ratosse aggro deck?
That deck might not exist. So like you
know this could be a best tootus and Z
play but I think as far as rate goes
this is about as good as it gets for a
uh for a charm. I think this card is
quite excellent. Um you know ratos
lizards or whatever else it might be.
Rats prowess of some kind. you know,
mostly mono black splashing red or
mostly mono red splashing black. Uh,
this card's nice, great limited card, of
course. Uh, best of show for multiolor
is Singer Quill Charm. And, uh, that's
some cool stuff.
Singer, Voxman, one mana for a one two.
Uh, every upkeep, you prepare this and
then again cast his vicious verse. So,
again, great uh, in your prowess deck
and in your stinger deal damage deck.
Uh, probably not good enough for
constructed, but pretty cool little
card, honestly.
Stinging vitrol. It's meant for a
thought seize. This is like a
blightening thought sees makeup. Uh,
it's meant for thought seize and they
take two, which is pretty good,
honestly, if you're aggressive black red
deck. Um, you know, is it better than
duress in like cyborg games? Maybe not.
But I think a fine main deckable card.
uh deals that deals that non-combat
damage. Trigger all your Singer Cool
stuff. Nice and card's good. Solid card,
fine. Unlimited, I think. A fringeish
player constructed, but definitely a
possible player. Um and again, really
cool art.
Ingress Stinger Quill. This is the
cheapest of the Elder Sphinxes. Black,
red, red for a 14 flyer. Uh whenever
creatur you control attacks, that
creature does one damage each opponent.
So, there you go. Boom. There's all of
your uh your non-combat triggers uh
being met. and four mana make a two two
haste
fine card you know so effectively at two
four for for three because it it counts
itself too uh then all other attackers
steal one card's pretty powerful I don't
know if it's good enough for constructed
uh but it it's reasonable you know it's
a hell rider adjacent uh and then having
a massic ability is cool too so sweet
cool card
onto vigor bloom and we've got emergency
phytoomeic
This is uh just a little guy but does a
lot of really cool stuff. One mana for a
woman and it's prepared. It plays seed
suture which is one mana. Put a counter
and gain one life. One of those cards
has a lot more than the sum of its
parts. So of course the green white
archetype is just life gain. Gain a
life. Do this. Cool. This is a way to
cheaply trigger that and trigger it in a
way where you could just play this. It
can hang out for a few turns, chip some
damage in, uh, and then they're not
going to want to kill it before you use
it, and you play your life gain card,
and super cheap, so you activate it
immediately and get your value. Cool.
Boros is also all about counters. So,
plus counters are a big deal in that
archetype. This is a mono white card
that can add counters to your Boros deck
and get cool synergy. And then on base
rate alone, this is a two two for for
two. They can attack on turn two and uh
and gain a life. Cool. That's great.
Play it on turn one. Turn two, pump it,
get it for two. That's great. The floor
is super high. The ceiling is great uh
for all your synergy stuff. Great card
in green, white, great card in red,
white, a serviceable card in other
decks. Ice is awesome. Big big fan of
the emergency photo. You're bombing
common. Noted that there only are 10
commons in the multiard section, so the
competition isn't that steep. Uh but
cards are great. Speaking of payoffs for
gaining life, we've got Bloom Brute.
Four mana for a 44. Gain life, draw a
card. Awesome, right? So, play this
thing. If you draw one card off this,
you're way ahead on ra and this card
could just take over the game. Then has
an ability of six mana. Gives a creature
trample and lifelink to end of turn.
Also cool. You know, if it's a common, a
Johnny's pride mate might be might be an
87 or whatever. And uh that's a good way
to do that, too. Trample also triggers
the ability card's great. It's just like
your typical lynch pin common for a
draft archetype. probably not good
enough for constructed uh but a bonkers
bonkers mythic uncommon unlimited
vigor bloom charm is your green white
charm and uh choose one target you
control gains hex proof and
indestructible draw card and gain three
and put a plus encounter on a creature
you control and it fights a creature an
opponent controls so two mana for snakes
skin veil not the best um two mana to
draw a card in game three so cycle
renewed faith not the
do better for a fight with a counter.
Fine. It's Dvoka's command which is
okay. I think this card is like a fringy
card. I don't know what deck I want to
play this card. If there was some green
white beatdown deck or whatever, I can
see playing one or two of his cards like
a change of pace kind of like, you know,
flexible, kind of hard to play around
kind of card, but not that overtly
powerful. Uh, great limited, you know,
super solid card for limited stuff. Um,
but yeah, I think a little too clunky on
the protection spell and the fight spell
is just, you know, fights aren't great.
So, it's fine. Good limited card, but I
think not quite there. I constructed.
Vigor Bloom Vanguard is two mana for a
tutu and it's prepared and each creature
you control with a counter on it as
vigilance and also has seed suture,
which is great. Uh, just super solid
draft card. Awesome.
Salarium sentry to meta for a three. If
an opponent casts a spell with mana
value two or less, you gain two life.
Watchwolf eats your heart out.
>> Pointless nostalgia.
>> Nightmare for aggressive red players,
right? Like you play a watchwolf that
gains two to four life. If you're going
to kill it, you're going to gain some
life. It has life gain synergy
potentially, but this is more of a pure
rate card, I think. Um, very solid,
great draft card, constructed I mean,
watch is noticed as it used to be. You
know, it was like green my creature deck
that could be a cyborg card maybe
against red decks, but it's just fine.
But great limited card
and oh my
>> good lord.
Kiwi Kiwa Vigor Bloom is the green white
sphinx and unbelievable
ridiculous bomb rare in limited
six mana for a 66 flying vigilance
lifelink ward two
gez
if you gain life make a black lotus that
part is surprisingly not that exciting
uh I think in limited you're just
ecstatic uh to make to have this
ridiculous a bane slayer with ward and
everything else. The lotus things only
once a turn so no combo loopy whatever
shenanigans. Uh that's more of a bonus I
think but yeah big hog and chunker
unlimited constructed not really good
enough. Uh but yeah I mean ridiculous
bomb unlimited really really cool stuff.
A lot of flavor text but for the most
part it's just big idiot with keywords
and that's normally very good enough.
On to Simic, we have Tam's Resistance.
Better for a sorcery hybrid. Put a
counter on a creature and it gains
vigilance. Empower Jace 4. So, at the
bare minimum, draw a card. It's pretty
good, honestly. You know, this is a
hybrid card. You can play this in your
blue red prowess deck. Play this in your
green white life gain deck. Uh, you
know, counter plus vual plus draw is
pretty good, I think. You know, like you
can't play it in red, white,
unfortunately, which really countered
matter a lot. But empower is great. Uh,
draw a card, leave a Jason play, get a
surveil as well. This card's solid. I
think card is a lot better than it
looks. It looks kind of fillery, but I
guess that's actually a pretty solid
common. I almost gave this the uh the
bomb in common award, but decided to go
with the uh the green white card. But
this card's good.
Kiora of Salt and Sand. The metaphor a
two four. Whenever you attack, if you've
activated a loyalty ability this turn,
untap target attacking creature and it
can't be blocked this turn. And then
planes walkers you control have minus 8.
Make an 88 Leviathan with hexroof. So
again, this is a signpost for blue
green. Blue green is all about Jayce's
mastery. It's about just empowering Jace
over and over and over again big time.
This can make your Jace make an 88
Leviathan with Hexroof, which is not
unbeatable, but pretty insane. Uh, and
this also just can get it for two and
and untap, which is kind of sweet.
Pretty cool card. Body's fine, too.
Blocks pretty well against against uh
with keep your J token alive. Yeah, fun
limited card.
Mind meanderer. Six mana for a 4-4
flyer. Has vigilance long as long as you
control a Jace Plainwalker. And when it
enters, you fight a creature an opponent
controls. Yeah, sure. Not amazing, but
enduring stomp power with flying is
pretty good. Just, you know, fine guy,
play it. Eat a 33. Totally reasonable.
Uh, good limited card. Not amazing, but
good.
Enrust the spark. It's a trap.
>> Not really a limited card, more of a a
constructed card. Five mana for a
sorcery. This is Tinker for
Planaineswalkers. Zakur Plaineswalker.
If you do search for a planaineswalker
and put on the battlefield,
that is a pretty powerful effect with
empower chase floating around, right?
You can end step empower Jace, untap,
cast this, get a plan walker. The
problem is that what's the best planes
walker in standard right now? Anyone
know class? It's Ugan. Seven mana Ugan.
You know the card with a cast trigger.
So you can go get Ugan. You can put it
in play. You won't get the cast trigger,
which is the important part of the card.
And are you playing Carlo's card
immediately? It's a stretch. Uh, so I
think this card's pretty sketchy. Uh,
you know, there are, I guess, like
there's six mana Johnny or five mana
else with whatever, but just like C at
that point, just cast those cards, you
know. So, I think this guard is kind of
cute, but realistically, just play a
good card. Why leave yourself at a spot
where you're going to like endstep
empower Jace? They're going to lightning
strike it, you're untap, just do
nothing. Just play good cards. So,
that's my trap card. Unlimited not
amazing either. Commander players have
fun. Have a good time.
Tam the possibility the metaphor a two4
and uh Tam is a serious story character.
I believe plans cost one less to cast
and you can Wooberg tap to proliferate X
times where X is the number of planes
walker types among planes walkers you
control. So interesting card. weird ramp
card for Planaineswalkers. This Wooberg
ability is pretty awkward. Anytime you
see Wooberg on a card, it feels like
commander bait. Uh so don't think this
card does too much. In limited, it's a
two four that doesn't really do much.
Constructed, it's two fours really do
that much. Commander players have fun.
Avatar of burgeoning Echoes again more
insanely awesome art. It's metaphor a 23
has landfall and power Jace 2. That's
good. That is that is quite good. Has
planes walkers you control have minus
10. Put a counter on each on target here
for each land you control. Not the most
insane payoff ability, but that landfall
ability is really good, right? Uh if
you're playing fetchlands, you know,
whether they're standard fetchlands or
modern fetch lands, it's empower four,
which is pretty po pretty potent.
That'll really add up. And the body
here, which two, two, three for two is
just fine enough, you know. Uh, I think
this card is, uh, it's pretty cool. I
don't know exactly what standard deck
wants this card, but it's pretty
powerful. Uh, unbelievable unlimited.
It's really, really good. Uh,
yeah, this adds draw card to all your
fetch lands. Pretty sick. Card's good.
Good enough. Not sure, but definitely
very good.
So, we got multiolor, our longest
section. We have best in show stinger
cold charm sleeper card the verasco the
cutting glare trap card interested spark
and our bomb in common is emergency
phyto medic ho is next folks make sure
you like comment subscribe support the
content we got one section left and I'm
done I'm out of here right so let's do
it if you miss any sections go watch
them on YouTube uh they're already
starting to go up white is already up as
well and uh they'll go go up over the